So I heard you want to edit videos like I do. When I wanted to up level my video editing,
this is exactly what I did. First, I picked a font bundle that was available on my preferred
editor. I paired one serif, one san serif, one script, and one handwriting. I was looking for fonts
that were simple and easy to read, matched my goal brand aesthetic, while also still felt like me,
like the handwriting font, I feel like looks like my handwriting. Then I decided to stick to like
go-to text animations. Type writer, bounce in, blur right, and golden dust are my favorites.
These are the ones that you see all over my videos. Then I paired the animations with a
matching sound. I found my favorite typing, whoosh, and pop sound effects. Sometimes I'll
add a little buzzer or ding, depending on what I'm talking about in the video. What's funny is I
actually picked a color palette initially that I was in love with, but I've noticed I actually just
stick to mostly white. I feel like it's simple, easy to read, and goes with every video that I post.
And then I actually implement my brand colors with what I'm wearing. Finally, my favorite thing to do
is color grading. I feel like this is where you can edit your videos to have the aesthetic
that you're going for, and I'll usually choose one or two go-to filters, and when I apply them,
I'll only apply them at 20 or 30%. Creators with a strong and immediately recognizable brand can
connect deeper and grow faster. If you're just getting started as a content creator and you're
barely figuring out editing, you don't need to have all of this, but when you're ready to up-level
your videos and become more recognizable as a content creator, you can implement things like
brand fonts, colors, animations, sound effects, color grading, etc. Over time, you will find your
signature style and become instantly recognizable.